# **Alfonso Wong**

San Diego, CA 92111 (760) 460-6036

Email: alfonsowongsd@gmail.com
Portfolio: https://www.alfonsowong.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alfonso-wong
GitHub: https://www.github.com/wongalfonso

Full Stack Developer with 1+ years experience in JavaScript, specializing in React/Redux. Possesses a Certificate from Origin Code Academy and B.A in Digital Media and Arts from California State Dominguez Hills. Looking to leverage my knowledge and experience into a role as a Front End Developer.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# My Life Unlocked – Internship/Wordpress Developer

Nov 2018 - Present

- Compressed Images for SEO.
- Integrated Member Press plug-in for user sign up.
- Created forms for paid users.
- · Edited and finalized media for subscribed users.
- Basic CSS styling for pages.

# Freelance - Full Stack Developer

May 2018 - Present

- Managed SEO through content optimization.
- Photographed and edited photos for clients website using Photo Shop and Premiere Pro.
- Designed websites for clients and built custom Logos and elements using Photoshop and Illustrator.
- Performed duties of a Project Manager such as making sure that all Media was available for website launch and Social Media campaign.

# Starbucks Coffee Company – Shift Supervisor

May 2008 - Present

- Helped create new clients and helped manage the needs of long-term clients.
- Received Partner of the quarter and Bean award for helping other stores in the district.
- Focused on Partner Development and adjusting to the needs of Partners that I manage.

# Daniel Obst Advertising – Audio Engineer

Jan 2012 - Dec 2015

- Redesigned and Updated a Digital Audio Workstation, Focused on the need of the agency and updated the specs to match those needs.
- Updated all computers and network to transfer all media into a cloud-based structure.
- Recorded and Edited audio for television and radio.

#### Studio West - Intern/Audio Engineer

Feb 2011- May 2012

- Recorded voice over's for television commercials.
- Recorded and Edited live performances.
- Recorded and edited various artists and Internet podcast's.

# PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

# **Programming**

MySQL Not my favorite, but It will do
 MongoDB Now that's what I'm talking about
 JavaScript The reason why I code today

• React/Redux It is a Framework? Is it a Library? Whatever it is, its my favorite

¡Query A fun Library to use

NodeJS npm install –save-dev react react-dom react-router-dom .... it never ends

Angular I've built a few forms using Angular 5, I'm impressed and would love to learn more

Webpack test: ∧.skills?\$/ use: {loader: "style-loader"} – you betcha
 Gulp haven't really had to use gulp, but I've got the basics down

AWS I've built a couple of EC2 instances, I'm not the greatest, but I know my way around

#### Designing

HTML A webpage wouldn't exist without this....

CSS If only there weren't so many screen sizes out there

Bootstrap Fun, quick and easy way to style your pages

Less

I know what we need... Lets add Math to your styling
Sass
I know its not JavaScript, but it can do so much more

FlexBox Not my strongest skill, but I'm working on it.

# **EDUCATION**

#### California State Dominguez Hills -

B.A. Digital Media and Arts: Audio Recording, June 2017

# Origin Code Academy

Certification of Completion, May 2018

# San Diego Community College City/Mesa College

A.A. Visual Performing Arts: Digital Music Technology, June 2015

A.A Liberal Arts & Science Business Studies

# Studio West

Pro Tools 8 Certification, May 2010

# **SKILLS**

Office 365: Word, Excel, Power Point If only they went back to perpetual licenses

PhotoShop, Premiere Pro, Illustrator, I have a good understanding of what all of these programs can do

After Effects and what they are used for

Avid Pro Tools

My whole professional audio career revolved around pro tools
Final Cut Pro

I stopped using Final Cut Pro when they changed it from 7 to X

Jira I'm not a scrum master, but I can sure knock out tickets

Git Flow Branches is the best way for version control

#### **PROJECTS**

# My Life Unlocked

#### http://mylifeunlocked.com

This is a website that was built using wordpress.com. All of the media was created by the owner, and I was given the authority to edit, compress and finalize all of the media. Integrated plug-ins, such as Member Press was an eye opener for me due to the fact that the plug-in required a specific format within the Wordpress template. All of the original images were too large for site and slowing down its initial loading. I used imageOptim to compress the size each image in order to boost its page load required for SEO specification. The page also needed basic styling which was added through the website.

# The Barberos BarberShop

# https://www.thebarberosbarbershop.com

This website is built in React using Sass for design. I created all of the media aside from the basic logo, I used PhotoShop, Illustrator and Premiere to create media for the businesses Social Media and Website. All of the custom elements were created in Illustrator such as the navigation bar and icons. The website is hosted on an EC2 instance in AWS using a Node.JS backend that allows for further customization.

# 1618 – Crypto Currency

This is a Crypto Currency that was built from scratch during JS meetups at 1618 held at 7 CTOs. This currency was created using JavaScript during a course of 6 Mob Programming sessions. I personally built the UI using React/Redux Framework because the project incorporated a user profile that needed to access an account that could then be manipulated over the course of a session. Although Redux will soon be phased out from Facebook's support, I understand how it works into detail and felt it would be a good tool to use.

# **Personal Portfolio**

# https://www.alfonsowong.com

This website is built in React using the LESS pre processor for design. All of the media was created in Photoshop, Illustrator and Premiere. I used Redux for all of the different forms that are included in the projects section and MongoDB for a route that will enable a user to sign up and adjust items on a specific portfolio. This Website is hosted on an EC2 instance with a NodeJS backend that includes Mongoose. I also integrated Google analytics to track the viewers of my portfolio.